# Antonio Martinez

antonios.martinez.dev@gmail.com +506 6017 0413 San Jose, Costa Rica https://martinezantonio.github.io/,

## Web developer

#### Summary

7 years of professional career as a web developer, participating in the product development of successful web applications.

Good understanding of PHP and modern JavaScript, using OOP programming and MVC pattern design. Excellent debugging skills and good webmaster concepts. (SSL, DNS, IP, Apache server, Nginx, IIS server).

Good understanding of web services and SOA-related standards like REST / OAuth / JSON.

A day in my life may consist of: Landing pages development, WordPress plugin development, adding an API endpoint, MySQL database design, read documentation of new PHP releases, fix some JavaScript bugs, back up websites, component and services programming in Angular CLI, add some form validation using JQuery, sending SMTP emails, API integrations and some more cool stuff.

## Professional experience

# Web developer

Jazz Gaming Solutions • San Jose, Costa Rica

01/2018 - 09/2020

I was responsible for developing, implementing, and maintaining mostly internal sportsbooks web applications like REST APIs, Websites, and Databases. I collaborated with technical and business staff in the design, development, testing, implementation, and production support of web applications in PHP, JavaScript, Angular CLI, HTML5, CSS3, Git, and some other cool technologies.

#### Web developer

PROFI · San Jose, Costa Rica

04/2014 - 02/2017

At PROFI, I mostly work with WordPress.

Working with project managers and designers, I was responsible for programming custom themes, custom plugins, mega menus, dashboards, reports, forms, landing pages, import, export, and backup websites.

## Web developer

CIP Reporting • Virginia, United States

08/2016 - 06/2017

At my current position, I am working on a web reporting system for casinos. Giving the maintenance and programming of new reports, new features, updates, and API integrations. We use technologies such as PHP, MySQL, jQuery, CSS, HTML, AJAX, JSON, Git. In addition to full-stack development, I also working on a lot of server-side tasks. I have helped to set up a lot of development environments and server configurations. (LAMP, WAMP).

#### Web developer

Netsoft • San Jose, Costa Rica

03/2013 - 02/2014

Programming and maintaining ERP systems. The principal, Dolibarr, a very robust open-source made in PHP. I was responsible for things like, develop new custom reports, migrate and export data in JSON and SQL formats, modify MySQL databases, PHP SMTP emails, templates design with HTML and CSS, API integrations.

#### **Technologies**

- PHP
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Git
- HTML
- ISON
- WordPress
- Apache

- MySQL
- Angular
- JQuery
- Bootstrap
- Sass
- REST
- Cloudflare
- Jira

#### **Education**

# **High school**

Liceo Ingeniero Manuel Benavides Rodriguez • San Jose, Costa Rica Currently completing courses in computer science, robotics and statistics

# Languages

· Spanish

· English

## **Projects**

https://mybookie.ag

https://xbet.ag

https://martinezantonio.github.io

https://plive.ganchrow.com

https://www.cipreporting.com

https://jazzsports.ag

https://scoresandodds.com

https://toyotacr.com

https://stayincostarica.com

https://tabacon.com

https://guachipelin.com

02/2015